<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tonny Mutai</title>
    <link>https://lestoni.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Tonny Mutai</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:35:36 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://lestoni.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mongodb Bulk Updates</title>
      <link>https://lestoni.github.io/posts/mongodb-bulk-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 00:35:36 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lestoni.github.io/posts/mongodb-bulk-update/</guid>
      <description>At one point, in your backend you will have a case where you need to update a bulk of data, due one reason or another.
In this case, i am going to focus on bulk documents updating in mongodb.
Setup Start off your mongodb shell:
$ mongod some_db Create a javascript file called bulk_write.js and add the following code . We will use this to in insert 10000 documents of receipts type document into the db.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://lestoni.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2018 09:33:44 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lestoni.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hello there, i appreciate you stopping by, my name is Tony Mutai or lestoni if you prefer. I live in Nairobi, Kenya.
I am a software engineer primarily specializing in designing and building of RESTFul API&amp;rsquo;s aka programming for the internets. The love for working with API’s stems from interest and enjoyment of working with web scale distributed and concurrent systems. I mostly code with NodeJS, Golang but i am working towards being a polyglot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Koncart</title>
      <link>https://lestoni.github.io/posts/introducing-koncart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2017 15:22:11 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lestoni.github.io/posts/introducing-koncart/</guid>
      <description>I am excited to announce the launch of koncart, an idea turned startup(ish) that i have been working on for the last one year plus. Koncart is a toolset company that empowers fintech ideas with Devtools and Analytics dashboards. It is currently in private beta.
The original idea was to build ECommerce Enabling APIs, which was conceptualized with my close friend and colleague in code John Adams and i. Fast Forward, i took the idea further after working with a few Fintech products and Startups and discovering some of the abstractions that needed a standalone platform.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Day and a Life</title>
      <link>https://lestoni.github.io/posts/a-day-and-a-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 20:16:27 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lestoni.github.io/posts/a-day-and-a-life/</guid>
      <description>To the reader of this book and the curious a like thank you for checking out this book.
Truthfully, this is was a random thought that crossed my mind. Having read some of the photography books, i thought i could write one too. I gathered some of the best photos i have taken and decided to do storytelling with them. Hopefully this is the first of many to come.
This is a self-published book and freely available for download.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Concurrency vs Parallelism</title>
      <link>https://lestoni.github.io/posts/concurrency-vs-parallelism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 14:10:11 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lestoni.github.io/posts/concurrency-vs-parallelism/</guid>
      <description>Difference between concurrency and parallelism does not resonate with most people, including me, for a while now. Until i started learning Go and everything became clear. Particularly with this one concise explaination that has stuck with me:
 Concurrency is a way to structure a program by breaking it into pieces that can be executed independently. Parallelism is about running those pieces simultaneously. Concurrency is about structure; parallelism is about execution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Blogging</title>
      <link>https://lestoni.github.io/posts/hello-blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Oct 2016 20:16:27 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lestoni.github.io/posts/hello-blogging/</guid>
      <description>I guess this is the hello world for blogging. For a quick introduction of who i am check my about page.
I started blogging-ish this year but slothed down a bit(Procastination is a habit and not good my friend). But with the ideas, lessons and what not i have picked along the way, i think its time i did something good and started writing.
With this blog i hope we shall learn, share, and engage together.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>